(Yowayowa Sensei)
(Episode 1: Kowakowa-sensei)
Mediocracy is the way of life.
That's the conclusion I've reached
after living for 16 years.
We're in the same class again.
A friendship with some distance.
- Yeah, we're classmates!
- Just regular classmates.
I wonder who's the homeroom teacher.
New semester.
ABIKURA
A 11TH-GRADE STUDENT STICKING TO MEDIOCRACY
So far, everything's been going well.
SNICKERS
If I could just get
a mediocre homeroom teacher…
What's that?
Is… is that a teacher?
She's muttering something.
She's definitely cursing us.
She's covered in blood and trembling.
Is she our homeroom teacher this year?
She's Hiyori Hiwamura.
On the first day of the new semester,
rumors spread that making her angry
would get you cursed.
They even nicknamed her Kowakowa-sensei.
I saw Kowakowa-sensei's notebook
covered in tons of talismans.
One day, she suddenly ran into me.
THUD
MUTTERING
And she said a bunch of
curse-like words.
Testimonies like this
were spread everywhere.
This is terrible.
Our homeroom teacher is that creepy lady.
This is not mediocre at all.
The… the water striders are red. Aiueo.
That's Kowakowa-sensei in there, right?
What's she doing here alone?
COUGHS
Among the floating algae…
O… okay.
W… well,
let's begin class.
Class?
But school's out
and there are no students.
EERILY
Is she
using dolls as students
to perform a curse ritual?
She's just as the rumors said…
First, let's review
the first-year material.
Opinion. What does this word mean?
GESTURING
Okay, please answer, Cuttlefish-kun.
Cuttlefish?
I… it means a view about something.
CORRECT
Th… that's right. Here's a credit for you.
Sh… she's playing both roles
in a role-playing game.
Next question.
C… could she really
just be practicing a class?
And she's practicing with dolls?
Okay, Pufferfish-kun, please answer.
It means the mood of a place.
Correct.
Anyway, her voice is way too faint.
Is my voice a little soft?
Oh, so she does know.
FEELING
That's right…
Take a deep breath,
and make your belly expand.
Then voice it.
POPS OUT
FEELING AROUND
Why?
Why did she take off her clothes?
Is she doing it to feel
if her belly is expanding?
She could feel it
through her clothes, right?
That's a different breathing technique!
PANTING
Ugh, her stamina is terrible.
But,
HEART RACING
How should I put it?
BREATHING HEAVILY
She's really weak.
I can't look away at all
HEART RACING
in every way.
Le… let's take a little break.
SITS DOWN
Wait, that chair over there…
You just moved it!
Look out!
I… I get stage fright easily.
My stamina is bad too.
And I'm always clumsy.
SHY
I finally achieved my dream
and became a teacher.
Yet I got assigned as homeroom teacher
in my first year.
So I thought I need to try harder.
Her… her voice is getting even smaller.
REVEALS
I tripped and hit the door this morning.
It made a really loud noise.
Everyone was startled.
That's why she was bleeding so much?
Oh right,
I need to check the next schedule.
Otherwise, I'll forget it again.
COVERED
They're not talismans,
CHANGED ENGLISH CLASS TO LITERATURE CLASS
but notes?
NEW TEACHER INTRODUCTION AFTER OPENING CEREMONY
She bumped into me.
So… sorry.
Sounds like she's muttering a curse.
I see. The mystery is solved.
My homeroom teacher
isn't a Kowakowa-sensei.
She has a weak voice
and poor stamina,
but she's a very hardworking
Yowayowa-sensei.
Um… I should probably get going.
Um… thank you.
Ex… excuse me, could you say that again?
Abikura-kun,
thank you for saving me.
I've fallen for her.
I can't take it anymore.
Ever since then, I've been thinking
about that strange teacher.
One, two.
CLASS 3-3, HIWAMURA
One, two, three.
SHIVERING
One, two.
Hiwamura-sensei?
Five, six…
Is she training her weak self again?
STRETCHING
PANTING
And what's up with that tracksuit?
It looks way too tight.
CLASS 3-3, HIWAMURA
That's definitely her high school jacket.
GASPING
She's already panting
just from warming up.
Go… good.
I should start today's special training.
Special training?
It's jump rope?
I see.
Even Yowayowa-sensei
should be able to jump rope.
S-Strange…
Hup.
It's not like it's double under.
How could she not jump?
TANGLED UP
Why does she look like she finished?
Ju… just a short break.
STUMBLING
If she walks like that…
Look out!
Abikura-kun.
Don't get me wrong, this is…
Our school's sports festival
ONE, TWO
in October
has a jump rope competition.
But my stamina is worse
than that of others.
To not drag our class down,
I thought I'd practice jump rope.
But it's only April.
In that case,
you maybe start
with basic fitness training.
Like exercising at home
to build muscle endurance.
I actually tried that.
But it didn't go well.
When I exert myself,
I unconsciously make weird noises.
It really bothers the neighbors.
What kind of weird noises?
Like her usual curse-like sounds?
But…
Abikura-kun, if you will help me,
I might be able to do it.
BLUSHING, STRAINING
What is going on?
No. I can't calm down at all.
I must find a topic to chat about.
Um… sensei?
Do you have an ideal type?
What?
What am I asking?
W… well…
My type
should be someone full of energy
who can give proper guidance
with a strong voice
and is deeply trusted by students.
I want to be that kind of teacher.
Oh, she means an ideal teacher type.
REALITY, IDEAL
And…
Isn't that the exact opposite
of her current state?
This is the weird noises
she mentioned earlier.
Yowayowa-sensei had weak athletic ability.
GENERAL STORE
Everyone thinks my homeroom teacher
is very scary.
KANJI PRACTICE BOOK
Kowakowa… no, Hiwamura-sensei.
Your notebook fell…
NAMI ITO
No! I'm sorry!
It's to remember students' names,
but does she need to write it
so many times like practicing kanji?
She tries very hard,
but she's a bit clumsy.
I wonder if there's anything
I can help with.
Hiwamura-sensei?
GLANCES
She's crying so dramatically.
What is she looking at?
Author's recent photo?
What on earth is written on it?
Yowayowa-sensei is even weak
in her tear ducts.
She's buying it?
It moved her to tears after all.
It does make me curious.
HOW TO OVERCOME STAGE FRIGHT
HIGH SCHOOL TEACHER'S COACHING TECHNIQUES
She's buying that kind of book again.
It makes me want to cry too.
FLUSTERED
Does she not have enough money?
No way.
Is Yowayowa-sensei financially weak too?
Um…
ALAS
Great, she does have enough.
READ BOOKD AND EARN POINTS
READ EVERY DAY
Would you like to buy a bag?
Each bag is 5 yen.
She brought just enough for books
and can't even find a spare 5 yen?
HOW TO OVERCOME STAGE FRIGHT,
HIGH SCHOOL TEACHER'S COACHING TECHNIQUES, GLANCES
I-it's fine.
It's not fine at all.
She is already fragile.
Now she's carrying
an umbrella and three books.
How can she possibly make it home safely?
Oh right.
Hiwamura-sensei!
COLLIDE
A-Abikura-kun, sorry.
I-it's okay. Um, well…
Sensei.
You can use this.
A bag?
I can't, I hate to trouble you.
This bag is a bit thin,
but better than nothing.
Thank you.
No way.
Amazing.
The plastic bag from you
protected my books.
My clothes got soaked.
But I really like reading.
Thanks for protecting them.
Her shirt is in big trouble.
Sensei, you'd better keep your coat on.
It seems Yowayowa-sensei
has bad luck as well.
Hiwamura-sensei?
Abikura-kun.
G-good morning.
Are you okay?
Why are you running so fast?
I'm not very good at waking up early,
so I overslept.
PARTIALLY VISIBLE
Yowayowa-sensei is weak in the morning
as well.
Today's second class
is my first class meeting.
I need to prepare early.
Bye.
Be careful.
And the button on your chest…
G-good morning.
Stay back!
But can she really handle it?
Class meeting lasts a whole hour.
She can barely handle
the morning assembly.
E-everyone,
class meeting
starts now.
SCARED
F… funeral?
She definitely said funeral.
The scary class meeting
FUNERAL CLASS MEETING
begins.
SHIVERING
This is a hellish start.
Everyone looks terrified.
Her handwriting is all wobbly.
She seems more nervous than usual.
What is that? Sutras?
Are we at a living funeral?
This isn't class meeting anymore.
Her face is a bit red.
Is she still not recovering
from the running this morning?
HEART RACING
SPLITS
Kowakowa-sensei…
She's holding a utility knife.
Is she
MENACING
charging up
to attack us?
Kowakowa-sensei doesn't throw chalk,
and she throws utility knives?
She definitely doesn't have
the strength for that.
She must have a reason for not moving.
This is my first class meeting.
Sensei, I want to be class president.
The first class meeting
of the new semester
will elect a class president, right?
Then I'll take charge from here on out.
This is agonizing.
This position is not mediocre at all.
Sensei, are you okay?
A… Abikura-kun.
Uh…
Could you help me get unstuck?
It's caught.
She's not wearing underwear.
I overslept this morning
and forgot to put it on.
Does that really happen?
No.
Judging by how flustered she was
this morning, it's definitely possible.
My leg also cramped up.
But touching the teacher's stockings
in front of the whole class…
Abikura-kun.
This is my first class meeting.
I don't want it to end in failure.
I… I'll help you now.
SHOCKED
DEAD SILENCE
FORCING COMPOSURE
Let's continue with the class meeting.
CLASS 2-2
Hey, class president.
Do my homework for me.
Shut up.
Although it was to help sensei,
I ended up becoming class president.
My perfectly ordinary school life
is crumbling.
What's this?
A challenge letter?
To Abikura-kun,
I would like to discuss
class management policies with you.
Could you please stay after school?
A private talk with sensei?
Long live the class president!
A… Abikura-kun.
Thank you for coming.
A megaphone?
Um… Sensei…
Aren't we supposed to discuss
class management policies?
Y… yes, that's right.
But at the faculty meeting today…
Hiwamura-sensei,
your volume makes it a bit hard
to hear you clearly.
Doesn't that affect your teaching?
CRUSHED
That hit the nail on the head.
So I thought this would
help my voice carry.
She's trying hard,
but increasing the volume
doesn't make her words any clearer.
I think it's a good idea.
The main reason everyone is afraid of you
is that there's a communication issue.
E… everyone is afraid of me?
She didn't realize?
Have I made them scared?
My… my heart aches.
No wonder.
I thought everyone seemed
to be avoiding my gaze.
Huh?
But Abikura-kun,
you can communicate normally with me.
STARTLED
Well…
Come to think of it,
I heard you weren't particularly active
in your first year.
But you volunteered to be class president.
Even though you were scared,
you still came to talk to me.
That's amazing. I respect that.
I… I feel like there's
a strange misunderstanding.
Anyway, the megaphone is a good idea.
Just try to speak slowly
and enunciate each word clearly.
I… I see.
W… water striders are red.
Great, I heard that clearly!
R… really?
Th… then if I stand on the podium,
will students in back rows hear me clearly?
Water strider.
I can hear you. Super clear!
OVERJOYED
Th… this way, they won't be
afraid of me anymore, right?
Definitely!
Can my thoughts really reach them?
They absolutely can!
Abikura-kun.
Did my feelings reach you?
HEART RACING
Yes!
What are we doing?
Thank you.
You're always helping me.
Not really, I haven't done much.
I just happened to
witness her trying her best.
HEART RACING
I might actually be falling for her.
But I'm feeling a bit tired.
FALLING
The megaphone fell!
That's an important tool for Sensei
to communicate with the students.
S-sorry, Abikura-kun.
I-it's okay. It was my fault.
TREMBLING
STARTLED
I-I'll get up right away.
Wait.
P-please don't talk right now.
We didn't discuss class management at all.
Let's discuss it another time.
Abikura-kun.
You're my ideal class president.
Let's do our best together.
Okay.
The strange misunderstanding continues.